{
    "id": "cc1c34b0c8534f24b5231bcd1f2b6007",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Which, Where, and What",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "37330e7af4fd4717a16ef3b418aa7d91",
            "title": "Relative Pronouns Which, Where, And What",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "This is the house .......................... I was born.",
                    "description": "Where can mean 'in which' or 'at which'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "which",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the town ....................... I spent my childhood.",
                    "description": "Where can mean 'in which'.",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the town .............................. I spent my childhood.",
                    "description": "Where can mean in which. Therefore, the first and the third options are possible here. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "which",
                        "in which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Do you know a shop ............................ I can find sports shoes?",
                    "description": "Where can mean at which",
                    "answers": [
                        "where",
                        "which",
                        "at which"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She got married again a few months later, ........................ surprised everybody.",
                    "description": "Which can refer to the whole of a previous clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "what",
                        "that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I was impressed by the way ............................. she did it.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "in which",
                        "what",
                        "that"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We have got everything ............................ you ordered.",
                    "description": "What means 'the things which'. It cannot be used as an ordinary relative pronoun after a noun or pronoun.",
                    "answers": [
                        "what",
                        "that",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the school ......................... I studied.",
                    "description": "Where can mean in which.",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "in which",
                        "where"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She may be late ............................ case we ought to wait for her.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "in which",
                        "in what"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We moved to the country so that the kids would have a garden .........................",
                    "description": "Both options are possible here. The relative pronoun is dropped in an informal style and it is more common to use infinitive + preposition.",
                    "answers": [
                        "in which to play",
                        "to play in",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the room .............................",
                    "description": "The structure with 'that' is common in an informal style. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "in which I was born",
                        "that I was born in",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The idea ......................... she put forward was interesting.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "which",
                        "what",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}